Jano González

Berlin, Germany | info@janogonzalez.com | github.com/janogonzalez

Profile

Software Engineer with 15+ years experience designing, implementing and operating highly available distributed systems that serve millions of requests per minute with millisecond latency.

Has led teams of up to 7 people, mentored 10+ engineers and presented in conferences like <u>LISA</u>, <u>RubyNation</u> and <u>JRubyConf</u>.

Experience

Staff Software Engineer - Contentful

Apr 2020 - Jun 2021

 Ensured a safe rollout of the GraphQL Content API to tens of thousands of customers by introducing a new tenant type with its own infrastructure and rate limits

Senior Software Engineer - SoundCloud

2014 - 2020

- Secured 6 extra years without space issues in the main database cluster by extracting social graph microservices out of a Ruby on Rails monolith
- Designed and implemented microservices using Scala and JRuby, coordinated the integration with 5+ engineering teams and safely rolled out traffic to millions of users
- Improved resource utilization by 50% and enabled multiple deploys per day by migrating the Ruby on Rails monolith from bare-metal to Kubernetes
- Identified lack of new contributors to the Ruby on Rails monolith as a risk. Mitigated the risk by introducing an ownership plan and aligning 5+ engineering teams around it
- Mentored 7 developers including colleagues and interns from the Rails Girls SoC program

CTO – Hopln 2012 – 2013

- Recruited and led a team of 5 developers to drive the transition from prototype to MVP
- Designed, implemented and scaled the backend to the first thousands of users

Senior Software Engineer - Continuum

2011

• Enabled legacy mainframe services to send SMS, email and social network notifications by designing and implementing middleware in Ruby and integrating it with a message broker

Engineering Manager / Project Manager - Taisa

2008 - 2010

• Led teams of up to 7 developers to deliver 2FA middleware used by hundreds of thousands of customers in banks and retail

Software Engineer – Depósito Central de Valores

2005 - 2008

Software Engineer - Everis

2005

Education

Software Engineer – Universidad del Bío-Bío, Chile

2000 - 2004

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby, Scala, Go, JavaScript, SQL, Java
- Technologies: MySQL, Kafka, Cassandra, Kubernetes, AWS, Prometheus
- Other: Distributed Systems, Site Reliability Engineering, Test Driven Development